okay so i see we have our
our first two o'clock panel that is
coming up and these are all people that
i have spoken to
um i actually have had the privilege of
meeting medea twice in person it's a
little bit like
it's a little giddy for me like it's a
little like it's
a little starstruck i have to admit
which you know um
so for anybody who does not know our
next panel is going to be
medea benjamin john kiriakou and kevin
gostola
so medea benjamin is the co-founder of
the women-led peace group code pink
and the co-founder of the human rights
group global exchange
she is arguably one of the strongest
figures on the anti-war left and has
done
on the ground activism for more than 40
years
john kiriakou is a former cia officer
former senior investigator for the
senate forum foreign relations committee
and he was responsible for blowing the
whistle on torture in our military
program and
he actually had to pay a very heavy
price for being uh speaking out against
that and so he is also a huge hero
and kevin gustola is um a journalist and
managing
editor of shadowproof he is known for
his work on whistleblowers wikileaks
national security and civil liberties
and he is also hosts the show
unauthorized disclosure with rania
khalik
who's coming on later so let me bring
everybody on
was that good katie great okay let's
bring everybody on
all right all right because i'm you know
i'm working it here
excellent hi all hey
hey hi good to be with you oh i'm so
glad you guys are here this is so good
um arguably this is the panel where
we're going to talk about treatment of
whistleblowers i mean that's going to be
like the key focus of this and um i know
that
katie what happened to you medea i
don't don't reveal the fourth wall okay
adjusting her thing so i shut it off
until she was
oh oh okay see all right i forget that
you have control of this too and i'm
like what's happening here okay okay
okay then you did
she's back all right so then you just do
it um and i know
that that katie who is infinitely more
um
experienced at moderating panels has
come up with some seriously good stuff
like to to do here okay yeah
well yeah welcome to all of you i've had
you
um all on my shows uh either useful
idiots or the katie helper show so
really excited to have you
um join uh in this discussion and it's
true you all are heroes
um you know medea for being this
tireless
um uh incredibly brave and
prolific protester uh and oregon she
still is by the way
she's still always i actually bumped
into medea in miami
at uh caravan for um for cuban
uh solidarity invented like the hands
off cuba hands off venezuela i saw her
at a car caravan recently
yeah on my bicycle jen oh you did it on
bike
yeah every time badass
i hope you're wearing a helmet no
no no we need you you're being selfish
we need you in the movement you cannot
we're not going during that please yeah
well anyway next time helmet please um
and then
kevin uh speaking of tireless totally
you know one of the most consistently
vocal people journalists to cover um
assange and uh you really it's it's a
kind of a sad state of affairs that you
are so unique in that role you should be
one of countless people who are covering
this story
consistently and of course i'm john
kiryaku
real hero and um the only person
the only person to go to jail to be
incarcerated
over the cia torture program so again
you should not be unique just like kevin
should not be unique
but you shouldn't be in there at all you
shouldn't be one of many but there
should be many people
who were actually punished for torture
but you were punished for revealing said
torture
um so i guess i think we could start out
by
talking uh about the
let's start with you john if that's okay
uh sure how you see yourself
and how you see assange and what both of
your cases reveal about the treatment of
whistleblowers
oh sure and also can you set up your
story in case people don't know about it
certainly and and before the hour's over
remind me
to say something about the effect of
calls to members of congress i spent
years on capitol hill
and they really do have an effect oh
well we can all do that i'm not even
kidding we can do that now
okay yeah i
and the senate side the senate's a
little tougher but in the house
you know sometimes they jump too with
just
one phone call or one letter they're
very responsive to constituents
on the house side so by all means email
call do whatever is easiest for you
because they'll they'll respond and
react to it
on the senate side they have usually
interns or young staff members who just
collate all the calls and the emails
coming in so if there
is a number of uh communications
coming in on an issue that will make its
way to the senator
so this is not a waste of time
this actually works i would encourage
everybody to call their their members
okay we have both numbers we have both
numbers the only difference is there was
something different if john
if you can remind me there was something
different about the thing with the
representatives that
obviously you have to know who it is and
they're so but we have all the numbers
we have everything there
and you can call 202-224-3121
which is the capitol hill operator and
if you don't know
your uh member the operator
is trained to identify who that is and
refer your call to the right office
can you say that number again i'm just
going to put it in yeah wait it's on our
phone script you see it on our screen
it's at the top of the script
yeah but i just want to put it in the
chat so they oh okay
okay so 202 you bet it's 202
uh 224 3121
great okay now we have it there okay
excellent so uh my name is john kiriakou
i'm a former cia officer
and uh to make a very long story very
short
i uh blew the whistle on the cia's
torture program in 2007
i was prosecuted by the obama
administration in 2012
and facing 45 years in prison i ended up
taking a deal that sent me to
a federal prison for 23 months where
where i had the fabulous support of
code pink and my friend kevin gestala
came to visit me a number of times
uh julian assange has always been
a beacon of
transparency and honestly i can't think
of
very many things that are more important
than transparency in government
one of the things that i like to repeat
almost as a mantra
because people just don't get it for
some reason is that julian assange is a
journalist
and even more than a journalist he's a
publisher
and what i don't understand is why the
mainstream media
is not lining up behind him because it's
clear to the rest of us
that if julian is extradited to the
united states and he's prosecuted
every one of these national security
journalists
at the washington post in the new york
times and the wall street journal etc
they're next and then who's going to go
to bat for them
so this is not me not me not if they
don't go to bed for julian no no
seriously i'm gonna i'm gonna snitch on
them
i'm gonna yeah they're serious i'm just
kidding
this has been going on for so long for
so many years that
everybody who needs to form an opinion
and come down on one side of the issue
or the other has had the time and the
opportunity to do that
so the fight's not over of course uh the
judge
while taking swipe after swipe at julian
in her decision
came down on the right side of it by uh
declining to
extradite uh kevin's an expert on this
issue yeah and you know there was a
there's precedent in the uk both in the
uk and in the european court of human
rights
to not extradite prisoners to the united
states because of the way that solitary
confinement is used as a punishment here
uh people lose their minds in solitary
confinement in the united states
you know it was newsworthy yesterday
when the state of new york announced
that they would abide by united nations
recommendations in not keeping people in
solitary for more than
15 consecutive days well that's great
but we're the only industrialized
country that
doesn't abide by that right
we've we've had people and medea and i
have talked about this
in other venues we we've had people in
the united states in solitary
confinement with literally no
human contact for as long as 44 years
now can you imagine not seeing or
speaking with another human being
for 44 years and then eventually you're
released from prison and you're expected
to live a normal life and be a
law-abiding citizen
it's outrageous but anyway
the issue here is is julian and i feel
like we're close but we're not
quite there yet and that's why we need
to keep up the pressure especially on
our elected officials and the justice
department as you're doing today
to make this thing go away it's amazing
to me that here in washington where
people are supposed to be so smart right
we're all the smartest people in america
here in washington
that they don't realize that this is a
pandora's box
and once that lid is opened and
everything comes out
you can't put it back in this is if
julian is extradited to the united
states
this is going to change the way the
constitution is interpreted
forever yeah forever it's a direct
assault on our first amendment rights
and so we're a little bit ahead of
things now
for the first time in many many years we
have to finish it off and win it
yeah and do you have any advice from
your um personal story
about what gets people interested or how
people
can be made aware of what's happening or
really this is an important story
thanks for that question katie i do i
feel like
when you're able to personalize things
people
sit up and take notice you know
sometimes
a story is so outrageous that
people can't help but to be interested
they can't help but to then offer their
support
i feel like this is one of those those
cases
because you know over the course of the
last
what 12 years from the beginning of the
obama administration
the definition of espionage has changed
in my view it's changed dramatically
it's been simplified which is very very
dangerous
the the courts now the federal courts in
the united states um
they define espionage as providing
national defense information to any
person not entitled to receive it
period now if you look at the espionage
act it goes for
you know 30 pages but that's the
definition that's used in court
well that could be you know you could
arrest a thousand people every day
for laying in bed before you go to sleep
and mentioning to your wife something
that you did
at work that day well you guess what
that's national defense information
so if a president doesn't like
what's been reported in the washington
post or in the new york times
with a president with a precedent of
julian assange having been
arrested and prosecuted then
again what's to keep those reporters
from being prosecuted
and as soon as those reporters are
prosecuted
that ends constitutional protections for
the rest of us
so i think that we need to personalize
this we need to explain to people
in plain english why it's so
important and why this isn't a fight
that's sort of off in the distance
between
um a transparency group and the american
government
this is a fight that impacts every
single one of us
that that's my guess number one yeah is
is personalizing it number two and i'll
say it again
especially on the house side
those members of congress jump when
their constituents
write letters because most people don't
write letters or
in today's situation emails
but um most people don't take the five
minutes
to write and express an opinion so when
they get
an email or 10 or 100 on an issue
they react to it i can't tell you how
many times
we would get a letter saying you know
please co-sponsor
hr12345 just because i'm asking you to
and we would read it and say well what
the heck is hr one two three four five
okay yeah well if this constituent wants
it sure we'll
co-sponsor that and we would we'd
co-sponsor it
now on the senate side when i was
working for john kerry in the senate
foreign relations committee
one call is not going to make a
difference but 10 or 20 calls are going
to make a difference
at the very least it's going to push the
issue onto his agenda
and so imagine what a hundred calls
could do
or 500 calls i mean that's real activism
right there
yeah so let me just say that
i just want to say that from anybody who
it doesn't necessarily feel comfortable
leaving a message
but we have a longer form of our script
that is also available that you also
you could use the script as an email as
well so if people do feel comfortable
sending an email but they don't really
feel comfortable calling please feel
free to copy and paste
um great and um medea i wanted to ask
you
as uh about your experience organizing
and what you think can make a difference
about
um in trying to get people to pay
attention to this story
uh if you have any advice besides
obviously the phone calls and emails
that we're all going to do
and in fact either during this segment
or during a break we should do them jen
and if any of you want to do them to
show what it's like
you can yeah well we'll yeah we don't
need to put people on the spot just yet
let's no i'm not putting them again i'm
saying if they not now if anyone wants
to do them just let us know
in the chat or whatever and we'll give
you the chance to do that but no
pressure um yeah i mean i'm not
asked medea to do that now but medea
what i will ask you to do
if you don't mind is share your
organizing experience
and any ideas you have for how to make
sure that people
do care about this and do demand
that justice be served basically for uh
julian
well thank you for doing this because
this is one of the great ways to get
people to care about the issue and learn
about
the issue and it's great to be on with
kevin and john um my um
connection to julian assange is really
through the information that he exposed
and as an activist and i think in terms
of getting people
to get active in this there were
hundreds of thousands if not
millions of activists who protested
against the iraq war
they should recognize that it was thanks
to julian assange that we learned so
much
about the horrific effect of that war
when i first saw the collateral murder
video i remember we played it we even
um had it on on screen so we would go
around to the homes of
people in power and and project it um
the uh files of not only iraq but
afghanistan taught us so much about what
our government was doing
the uh guantanamo files i mean now
there's still a a
group that's been active all these years
to try to close guantanamo they should
also be
part of this effort to free julian
i think among the issues for which
julian has gotten a bad rap
it's ones among the liberal community
and as you know
it was the release of the information
about uh hillary clinton in the dnc
files and john podesta's files right
before the election that really
got him the uh the the the hatred
um uh from a lot of uh democrats
i think we have to explain to people
that uh julian's job in the job of a
good journalist is just to expose
things the truth no matter what side is
going to be hurt by it
let's remember he also exposed um
information about sarah palin he not
only
pissed off governments that were the
around iraq and afghanistan but also
around the arab world in general the
corruption of the arab world that really
helped to spark the arab spring he
exposed the
um scandals within the turkish
government he exposed scandals in peru
he exposed the um
the issues in uh in iceland
that led to a lot of shake-up within the
government there
um extrajudicial extrajudicial killing
by the
police in kenya when you are somebody
and an organization that exposes all of
these things
you're going to make a lot of enemies
along the way and that's what happened
to
julian assange and so i think it's
important
in terms of the low hanging fruit of
people who should care about this
is to get people even within the social
justice movement
to recognize that exposing the truth
is something that helps us even if it
exposes things
about a group that we might be
sympathetic towards or a government
we might be sympathetic towards and
i um think that in in terms of the kinds
of things we have to do
um well i've been involved around julian
in a lot of the the uh protests that
have been going on in
england and it's really great to see
how they have branched out and brought
people in
from the government like jeremy corbyn
uh they've brought people in from the um
the world of uh the artists and the
um uh and the writers and
uh they've really reached out into a lot
of different sectors of society
and i know we've done that for a certain
extent
here um there are people in the
hollywood scene like oliver stone that
have come out very strongly in favor of
julian
uh but i think there's more we could do
in terms of getting
influencers to uh speak out
and uh then i agree with john you know
it's a covid time so it's harder to get
out on the streets and
uh do the kind of protests we need to do
which is why it's
even more important during these times
to uh do the calling and the emailing
uh and the online kind of activists the
tweeting and the instagrams and the tick
tocks and everything we can do in the
social
media to get people to know and care
about this issue so i just wanna you
know
say thank you for the kind of
educational work you're doing with this
uh almost day-long uh webinar and
uh well it's not a webinar is it what do
you what do you call it
i'm calling it a it's a livestream
telethon live stream telethon
and i love that there's an action
component to it and i will certainly do
it
during this time and i encourage
everybody who's listening
to not only absorb new information that
you can
help spread the word to other sectors
that might not know enough about julian
and might just have heard uh rachel
maddow
or uh somebody else that that you might
um
uh like as a a broadcast journalist
trashing him
um but uh you also have to
uh put the the focus on our
uh elected officials and i just wonder i
don't know um
who of our elected officials is there
anybody in congress who's already come
out
openly in favor of releasing julian
i have not seen anybody no uh the
closest i've seen the closest i've seen
is
nina currently running she actually just
put out something
um supportive of julian assange and i
actually would have probably told her
not to do that
but she she did a few days ago yeah um
and that's the closest i've seen i
haven't seen anybody sitting in congress
that has spoken out in favor of julian
assange and why would you have told me
that
that's nina turner for people now you
know i would i would say
once she's in she should let it all fly
but i think right now the goal is just
to get her in there and she's got a very
short little span here between now and
election day so just like sort of from a
political perspective
that's actually why i when i messaged
her about this
i um was very clear like i don't think
this would be a good move for her i just
i
i think that not yet um yeah so that
would just be
you know just caution yeah i see what
you mean but people who are
already uh income exactly we should
definitely be pushing them not only
in what we write to them but but also
really trying to get them
to be public uh to put out some
information some statements a tweet or
something
uh because if you compare all of the
people in the
uh british parliament in the labor party
for example there are lots of them who
have come out
uh publicly and to compare that to the
u.s
where uh the our it's our government
trying to extradite
him and charging with so many uh
different uh
charges that it could be 175 years in
prison i mean we should certainly be
getting people
and not just democrats libertarians you
know certainly people like
rand paul um yes uh we should be pushing
them to come out
and i was trying to we were jokingly
kind of but trying to get um
trump to own the libs before he
got out of power by uh hurting it by uh
pardoning assange what else we
wanted him to wha what what is the ask
for you john i'm sorry
the legal yeah it was pardoned you know
there's a little bit of a story
even though you're yeah we had we had
asked for assange snowden and me
and um you know i hired a lobbyist and
and i had some reach into the white
house tucker carlson
sort of adopted my cause and um
i i really believed i was gonna get it i
i actually believed for a little while
that all three of us were gonna get it
and then what i heard from a well-placed
person at the white house
is that it was mitch mcconnell that
called over and said
if you pardon these three you're going
to lose the impeachment trial
and so none of us got it well oh that
mitch mcconnell
always there with such a right hand such
a helper
he's yeah he gives a terrible name and
does terrible pr for turtles by the way
so uh i just want to say that not all
turtles um and one other thing i would
just want to point out is that if
publishing this information were so
treacherous then we really need to be
going after the new york times the
guardian everyone who reported on these
stories
because you know you have to be
consistent and either it was not
uh cautious not prudent to cover these
things which i would of course disagree
with but if that is the argument for why
assange is such a you know a
disreputable person
um such a pariah then fine but also go
after the places that publish this
and um it's also incredibly
infuriating that much like john you were
the only person to
go to jail over cia torture um we have
not torturers
just the first hand rose is the torture
because that's logical
no right that's what i'm saying he was
the only right no but he didn't do it
but i'm saying
from the revelations about the torture
the only person who was punished was the
one who revealed it not the ones who
engaged in it and um uh likewise you
know
their manning and assange helped bring
to light the collateral murder
video which again no one is talking
about the fact that
there was captured on video the um like
really brutal um killing of
uh civilians of members of the press
of the people who try to help the people
after i mean literally you have this on
video they're trying to help the people
who are shot
and they decide to shoot those people
too and they're they're animate you know
they're narrating it in a way as if it's
a video game
and no one wasn't got in trouble for
that except for the people who helped
expose that um uh
kevin wanted to ask you about what it's
been like covering these stories
and um why you think there's such a
deafening silence around it
well yeah so i i think that first let me
say thank you to
medea and john it's great to be able to
be part of this panel and thank you for
organizing this telethon event it's
extremely crucial
what we're doing here and just in
general before i get to your question i
wanted to
throw out my own opinion about the the
distinction between
donald trump and barack obama i get a
lot of pushback from people who seem to
think
that it's the same there's not really
any difference and
and in fact they'll point to the grand
jury investigation
uh and they'll say that that was opened
against julian assange
so donald trump charging julian assange
is not that much different because
they were investigating julian assange
because there was this cloud of
investigation that ultimately drove him
to seek asylum from the ecuador
government
and i just would say that we have to be
very specific about the timeline of
events and what actually happened
we can point to charges being entered
against julian assange by
the trump justice department we can't
find
an identical example under barack obama
there simply
aren't charges on the record from the
obama administration that were brought
against julian assange and so like that
right there
is enough in my head to say that there's
a difference
and the other thing is as activists we
have to be
sensible and recognize that this
difference is
something we can leverage to get the
outcome we want
for julian assange the fact that it's
barack obama who chose not to prosecute
assange
is something that you can mention
repeatedly
until you finally get the result that is
necessary which is dropping the charges
because that's somebody who's part of
our team
well not my team necessarily but like
the team
the fact that you know if he was if if
barack obama was the person who started
the investigation against assange i
would tell you
that this struggle would be
astronomically
more difficult and we might not even
have a chance
um and so um that being said you know
my experience covering this and with
journalists is just that
for the most part people who are
in the media do feel what you talk about
katie and
and what matt tieby talks about that ick
factor they really do
feel that if they touch this um
they are going to be in in trouble that
it's going to jeopardize their ability i
i feel like they
think they're going to get blow back
from their audience there's just so much
propaganda
out there about julian assange i would i
would wager
that almost 90 percent of what we think
we know
about julian assange is mostly
propaganda
um at least what people think i mean i'm
a reporter so
hopefully what i am putting out there
isn't propaganda hopefully
what i'm reporting is something that i
can substantiate
and share with people based on things
that are true and
and from sources and people who are
advocates who
who truly are um good for for
for julian assange and wikileaks and
they're not there to demonize him
um but i think most of what we know what
we think we know
um whether it involves the podesta files
or um whether it involves the the
swedish case which i know is such
such third rail that we just avoid it
but but honestly
um i think it's to the detriment of all
of us
that we treat it as such a third rail
because there are some incredible
due process issues with what the swedish
prosecution authority did
that uh we we make our job even more
hard when we ignore it and and pretend
like
it didn't exist that being said i think
you know what we need to do here is
exactly what john was saying
is to is to personalize this to boil
this down to those
those things that um make it really easy
for people
to tap into and care about this
the story and to stand up for it
this is a father he has two children
he has a partner he is being kept
in a prison in indefinite detention
and and he's being treated um in an
extraordinary way
especially considering that what he did
um
even even if you believe in
decarceration and and
and restorative justice he has not been
accused of any violent crime whatsoever
and yet he's being
held in belmar's prison during a
pandemic
uh where we know there have been
outbreaks in the facility
he was spied on by uc global a
private security company that targeted
journalists
on behalf of we believe the cia i mean
it's a massive scandal that
only spanish media seems to really care
about because there's a spanish case
that has been filed
in spain again and it's a spanish
company yeah
because it's a spanish company against
and primarily the director david morales
is the one who's in trouble for that but
this is something
that if you talk about the treatment and
the way they went after julian assange
you should be able to get people to see
that this was about destroying a family
this was about finding out who the
identity was of babies who were being
brought
into the embassy this is about
identifying
who was the lover of julian assange so
they could go after so this is classic
for people who
have followed the history of
activists and organizing in the united
states we know that this is how
the national security estate works to
demonize people so it's very
classic in the way that this contractor
went about targeting
julian assange assange you know finally
i would just say
that this is a bit of a nitpick but i
think it's interesting for our
conversation
most of the time when you hear
journalists in
the media talk about this case they will
call julian assange the source or they
will call julian assange a whistleblower
or they will say he's the leaker it's
very deliberate
what they're doing there but i also want
to say that it's impossible for him to
be the leaker
because he's not working in any of these
agencies he doesn't have
access to this information he's not the
one who
has chosen to disclose this information
to the public
he's the publisher he's the journalist
he's the person who's taking the risk
with his organization
to do the work necessary to have the
security
to authenticate the documents to make
sure they're not forgeries
and wikileaks has a pretty i think
99.99 record of being able to verify the
authenticity
of all the documents that they've ever
filed on their website there's maybe
only a handful of documents you can
question
and they didn't make any news headlines
so they don't really matter
and uh and you know that's that's his
job
and and so i think um it's up to us
to do this work this this telethon is
important
because we're destigmatizing julian
assange we're demystifying all of this
our politicians the elites have made him
out to be this boogeyman
figure and then with our work which can
be difficult
we're gonna tear all that apart so that
people can see the essence of
what julian assange did and what
wikileaks does and appreciate it again
because they did they did before the
elites got to it
and then now um the the next generation
of people
only know julian assange based on how
elites
teach them about julian assange and
wikileaks
and it's up to us to unravel that can
you actually since you brought this up
and you said that we
avoid the swedish um uh
case to our detriment can you give a
short a quick overview of what that is
i find people still harp on that yeah i
find that that
he still gets referred to as in some
sort of sexual predatory way
even though that was a complete
fabrication and that that has lingered
and i think that they knew that would
linger and i think that that's the one
of those things that
keeps the sort of liberals sort of
anti-julian assange yeah or it's an
excuse for them too but
yeah kevin can you shed some light on
that yeah
and i i have a very um me too safe
answer for how this you know
this is what we should say this is this
is the way it was
they started and stopped the
investigation
into julian assange no less than three
times
no less than three times did the swedish
prosecution authority
open and close open and close and open
and close
the investigation and there technically
weren't ever any charges issued
against julian assange there were
allegations
that they were investigating they were
told
not to go to the ecuador embassy that
the prosecutors
were told they couldn't go to the
ecuador embassy and question assange
in the embassy under the treaty or
agreements that uh that sweden has
with the uk because the british
government actually applied pressure to
prevent
the swedish prosecutors from coming to
the uk to to have that they wouldn't
allow for
so then there was some conversation over
whether they could do this virtually
um with julian assange in the embassy we
know a lot of these details thanks to
journalist
stefania moritzi who i know you talked
to very useful
idiots um and she's you know i mean i
just want to give her quick credit
on this show she's one of the only
journalists i know
who has had the guts to push freedom of
information act requests
against all the governments implicated
in this entire scandal
of of this case against julian assange
but finally i would just say that if you
care
about the women that uh and whatever
went on in in the bedroom you know that
night with
with julian assange if you if you care
about that if you care about
valuing their experiences and believe
that you know again like
let's just pretend like i don't know
anything about who these
women are and i know that there's been
some some claims about
whether you know one of them is
compromised by the us government
or not let's just pretend like let's set
that aside let's pretend like these are
just
women who had a bad experience with
julian assange if you want to value
them then what the swedish prosecution
authority did
is the absolute wrong way to
take care of people who are bringing
sexual allegations because you are
allowing
it you're allowing a case to be
politicized and manipulated by
world governments you know for the
purpose
of keeping a publisher in limbo who
has been exposing corruption by
a powerful government and so i think
that it's it's pretty simple it's it's
pretty simple if you want to talk about
this
you raise the due process issues and you
connect the due process violations
to the due process violations that are
existent right now
in the extradition case and some of the
other
inequities that are existent in this
case that have been that has been
brought against julian assange
yeah um
and uh does anyone want it i mean i
i guess i can do a phone call do you
want me i have it set up better
well i already did my calls
people should see somebody do it well
have you called your person called
the department of justice because
they've heard from me a couple of times
right where's the script i'll do it hold
on i'm putting it up i'm going to put it
up
um we just want to make sure people you
know
want to encourage people to also by the
way sorry one more thing
the story about the spying is incredible
absolutely incredible and the fact that
it hasn't been covered i mean i i
brought up the fact that it was covered
by
you know spanish uh el pais because uh
more understandably it's about a spanish
company but they spied
on assange and they
even tried to um go
through the guard they did they took out
his
children's um his son's
diapers to try to do a dna test at that
point they didn't know it was
they were his children um and they are
so stupid by the way that they think
there's dna
that you can do dna from stool but
that's another issue
but they did that can you i mean these
are this is the level and it was such a
disgusting invasion
that that's what brought some of the
people working for the spanish
company to tell um correct me if i'm
wrong uh
kevin but i think it's she said this to
us on useful idiots tell his partner
stella morris that they actually came
over they told her
not to bring the kids anymore because
they were doing that
you know they were taking the samples
from um
their nappies i guess as as they say in
the
in different countries um their diapers
and that is just a really repulsive
thing
and what's really scary about this is
that despite the fact that this was
revealed none of the mainstream
reporters right the woman um
ellen yeah ellen nakashima nakashima
from her washington post
her cell phone battery was taken they
tried to take her cell phone battery
from
her and and we get no objection the
washington post won't put out any press
release
standing up for their reporter yeah it's
absolutely probably i mean it's
disgusting
um if medea you want to make this on
speakerphone so everyone can hear it
uh yes i i'm leaving my message now
hello my name is medea benjamin and i'm
calling from washington d.c
to ask that the united states drop the
case against julian assange
i am very concerned about the
ramifications
that persecuting a journalist for
exposing american war crimes will have
on
our civil liberties joe biden said that
he would end trump's attacks on the
press
yet his administration has indicated
it's going to continue to seek
assange's extradition the prosecution of
assange creates a dangerous precedent
that will prevent journalists
from holding our government accountable
please protect our first amendment
rights
and drop this case against assange
immediately
thank you for your time bye-bye all
right
so i would just say
that we should tell people which button
to press when they um
uh contact the comment line did you
yeah i mean it was the one if it was the
one if you want to make a comment on on
civil
liberties or constitutional issues i
mean it you get
two options in the beginning where they
basically say this is an emergency
call the fbi and um then there's the
if you want to make a comment on issues
regarding civil or constitutional rights
um i think it's push one john yeah so
you can do one
or you can do the general comment line
would be which would be nine
so either okay uh that was great thank
you for doing that and i'd have a shout
out to john holder our producer
who yeah option one who has really done
an amazing job and put this together and
um
yeah and so everybody it is down in the
description feel free to use it feel
free to use it and convert it as an
email
yeah great great script john yeah
and i gotta get the house gov that's how
i find my uh congresspeople house.gov
yeah and we are hearing from people that
a lot of shockingly dianne feinstein's
uh
mailbox is full um and so was and mitch
mcconnell
so obviously obviously there's gonna be
certain people that you're just not
gonna be able to get through to uh
and apparently joe biden um but i would
just say honestly i think it's most
important that we hound the department
of justice at this point now that
merrick garland is in there so i i think
really that's the
that's sort of the key one right now
yeah yeah agreed and we should do some
kind of a
protest or a rally at the department of
justice is there something planned
well there was something that they there
have been things going on this past week
i don't know
if kevin if you know anything about that
they had some stuff going on in dc this
past week
um regarding assange a lot of the
activists
um were doing something on the street
out there i think that somebody even put
something about that
i'm just loosely familiar that there was
a st patrick's
day timed event clovers yes and
that's what it was and usually they
would pick
the you know the target would be to go
to the justice department
yeah but i agree i mean the more the
merrier
and is it the um assange defense
dot org or um
yeah uh that did the one it was the
clovers was what it was that did
this it was cl i even i put up that it
got lost in the comments
it was clovers for assange i believe
as far as i know that wasn't an assange
defense committee protest it was
an another more loose uh more grassroots
loosely knit group but
uh uh but yeah the assassin's defense
committee has
organized rallies and yeah i do i do
agree with medea that there there
definitely should be something
yeah well the nathan who we had on in
the very beginning um
his information and his organization um
that stuff
is available in our description and
that's the organization that is pretty
much on top of all things that are
actions involving julian assange
which is how we ended up getting their
assistance with this
so i would suggest that people go there
um and check it out because they keep
everything current whatever actions are
going on for julian assange
and i would also just say in case people
don't know who their um
rep is uh you can go to
uh housegov dot
uh house dot gov
slash representative slash find you know
what it's a little hard to yeah just
type you can just type in there
because uh and that and that way you'll
actually get to see who
your representative is and then you go
to the other thing the the house.gov
representatives and it's it's listed by
either name or by
state um but this is a way that you get
it by
um by your zip code
so yeah i can i can do that um
maybe one of us can do it per uh per
per segment yeah i mean i i think that
yeah i think that's good i gotta call
chuck even though the senate
i just want to call chuck schumer anyway
i like to check in on him you like to
talk you like to chat with chuck
yeah yeah you know yeah ask him about
that who his favorite um classmate is
from that high school that he went to
uh bernie went to uh rbg uh
uh norman finkelstein anyway um but i
digress yeah i mean it really is again
it's a total stain can you imagine that
they want the script back can someone
bring back okay all right all right all
right all right i got it all right
mallory
all right and also thank you mallory and
also can you just imagine again
that you were a washington post reporter
who had your cell phone meddled with and
you decide it's not worth
raising your voice why do you guys think
that is by the way
oh i know the answer to that question
because if they say
something then people are going to
accuse them of being assange supporters
so like you're actually supposed to want
to be the victim
in this case like you're supposed to
want to be targeted on behalf
of the caa does did john media disagree
no i don't disagree at all i hate to say
hey you just want to martyr yourself
you're supposed to marry yourself for
this
military industrial complex right well
and look at the way
look at the way intelligence reporting
has changed over the years too
where where once upon a time reporters
tried to develop sources like you do
kevin to you know give them information
or confirm information on intelligence
issues
now we have the likes of kendallenian at
nbc and msnbc who
who got caught sending his articles to
the cia
for clearance before he sent them to his
own editor
i mean it's more efficient right it's
more efficient sorry
cut out the middleman exactly yeah you
don't want to cost your editor to do
that extra work
it's good nice very considerate yeah i
have a question for kevin well
and and you jen well erin anybody might
know
um it does seem that some of these
organizations for the protection of
journalists have come around
and been supporting julian that is that
the case
yeah yeah i can't think of a single
press freedom organization
that has not come out in support of
julian assange
now the problem i have with the
committee to protect journalists
which i wrote about was at the end of
the year
i want to say in 2019
so this would have been the same year
that julian assange was
arrested and mind you we're coming up
just to be clear we are coming up
on the two-year anniversary of him being
tossed from
the embassy but the the committee to
protect journalists
refused to list him as a jailed
journalist in their end of year
index of people around the world
who are to be and then they knew that
they were going to get a backlash
so incredibly and this is why i wrote
about it was
they put up a blog post on their website
explaining why they could not classify
julian assange as a journalist but just
to be clear ridiculous no matter how you
view him
he's paying dues to the international
federation of journalists
he's actually a union member of a
journalist organization which in my book
no matter what you think of a person
that makes you a journalist
automatically
so there shouldn't be anything more but
that being said
you know uh he's not even a
he's not even a u.s citizen so our
metrics for how we recognize
who does and does not have uh first
amendment rights
you know it's sort of like we need to
have a global sense
about all of this and the global sense
is that everyone is entitled
to this freedom of expression should
have these
protected rights and all these
organizations have recognized that i
would say
you know if we want to look upward
rather than punching downward
the the people at reporters without
borders
and rebecca vincent have been truly
remarkable
in their advocacy for julian assange
she's used her platform in the uk
to to call attention some really
important issues
on the ground in the united kingdom as
well as with the julian assange case
and my other question is have we seen
any kind of divisions within the
you know the big papers like washington
post in the and the
new york times i remember seeing uh the
very negative ones about julian but have
there been positive ones
as well
yeah i don't i don't i don't think
there's been a whole lot
of reporting on the assange case
beyond the immediate reporting on the
arrest
and you know so what's really sad to me
is when i was logged in
during the pandemic and mind you if you
had just had some kind of awareness
whether we're talking about the new york
times all the way down to
the intercept all you had to do was
send in a request to the courts and you
could get a media credential to cover
this
they would give you a login because of
the pandemic
i feel like we should have had greater
access and did have greater access
to the extradition trial and there's
really no excuse for any journalist or
media organization to not be covered
because you didn't have to spend
resources and money to travel to london
from the united states in order to cover
the extradition trial
but there really were mostly european
journalists
some people from other parts of the
world and a
limited a highly limited number of u.s
journalists that were in there
following the extradition trial me being
one
of the only ones waking up every morning
at 3 a.m to follow the extradition trial
from the united states and i just i i
think they did the bare minimum most of
these media organizations have done the
bare minimum
and they need to come back to it now but
somehow i feel the election of joe biden
makes it harder for them to just to
write about this case
yeah of course because i think that
you're talking about people with
significant amounts of corporate donors
and and those donors and their
advertisers are not wanting anybody to
speak out on behalf of julian assange
they're just not they're they're just
too they're they're too corporate owned
and
they just do not want this out there and
i also think that the mainstream media
is very threatened by people like julian
assange and their numbers are
increasingly going further and further
down and they don't want independent
media and people like julian assange
exposing things
um they're not doing it themselves mind
you but they don't want anybody else to
do it either
yeah it's i mean it's really again i
can't get over how shameful
it is that this is not front page news i
mean remember when the
no one was covering barely anyone was
covering the uh the ruling
um the treatment of this has just been
so incredibly biased um
it's mostly been just ignoring the case
and i do think
again like you were saying kevin what
people who who
like obama you need to be pushing the
obama
um approach to this not the not the
trump one and for people who like trump
um there was something i was going to
say oh
for people who are republicans uh john
the only person who advocated for you
getting your pension am i correct there
was one senator who advocated for that
and that was john mccain right john
mccain
yes for you republicans out there got to
follow that lead
yeah so i got the liberals covered i got
the mccain republicans and
if you like trump you know okay he did
at one point
well yeah if you like trump just know
that a son that assange is
hated by hillary clinton and there's
nothing that hillary clinton would
dislike more
than to see him freed so for everyone
out there
who doesn't like hillary clinton you
definitely want assange to be freed
but if you like hillary clinton like
obama
you definitely want uh him to be freed
so that trump and pompeo are not the
calling shots so you're
everyone's covered katie the the
ideological spectrum is not a straight
line from left to right it's a circle
and it meets at some point um that's why
in the past year i was on the tucker
carlson show
nine times right he has a lot of wacky
extremist ideas
but on the issue of whistleblowing and
the issue of julian assange and ed
snowden he
is right on and so this really is
something that the left and the right
can cooperate on we both want
uh freedom of expression freedom of
press transparency
governmental accountability this is
there's no reason that we can't all
cooperate on this
right and i would just add the broader
demand
in addition to julian assange has to be
that we
end these espionage act prosecutions
against people that we saw
under you know the trump administration
and that we really saw
escalate and pick up under barack obama
and then also
in this same vein we have a
huge issue with people being stopped at
the border
u.s border with canada or mexico or just
coming into airports we have a huge
issue
with journalists having their devices
seized um and and
people who are especially uh connected
to um
the kind of independent or alternate
alternative journalism
and that impacts upon wikileaks and this
other
stuff so so you know there are there is
a
agenda for freedom of the press that
having these charges dropped against
assange fits within
and that's important right and everyone
who believes in that i don't care where
you you know i may not like what you
have to say but i'll fight to the death
to protect your right to
to say it all of those principles
there's really nothing controversial
about
about this it should be very
straightforward
um it's a you know it's freedom of press
and uh everyone should be afraid of
of and disturbed by the possibility of
uh julian being kept um in prison and
also
you know this is not i don't his health
is not great
and um he's being exposed to covet and
this really if this happened in another
country
the united states would be condemning
this as a crime against humanity as an
example of like a corrupt
country oh we would use it as an excuse
to we would use it as an excuse to send
people we'd be sending
troops in to help those poor people yeah
yeah
yeah so um any closing remarks from from
people on the panel and thank you so
much again for doing this
no i just had another uh uh a thought or
question
about uh um trying to push
eric holder to say something
tweeting at him that's interesting ooh
that's a cool
he knew i mean he definitely had the
wherewithal to know that this was not a
good
a good where to go forward like he knew
that this was this was not
good for all of us so um yeah that's a
good idea
i mean another idea is getting these
people who were in the justice
department
who have left and there we know that
there were a couple
during trump's uh presidency who
defected and did not want to
be a part of this prosecution it was
reported
in the i think the washington post
actually reported it that there was
division
over whether to bring charges against
julian assange and
so identifying those people getting them
to speak matthew miller is someone whose
name came up multiple times
during the trial the extradition trial
and he's the person who was on record
for saying
why the uh the the obama administration
couldn't charge
julian assange so getting him to speak
might be something
that could have some kind of influence
over joe biden
that's a person we don't know but joe
biden certainly knows
and merrick garland and the justice
department uh the top
high-ranking officials there are
certainly going to pay attention and he
was eric holder's
uh chief spokesman so maybe he could
even get us to hold her
that would be called john you want to
reach out and not you john john who's my
producer who's in the in the comments
john my producer who's listening um he's
the person who sends out our information
if you want to reach out to matthew
miller that would be really cool
and uh see what we can come up with
oh well thank you guys so much and
anything you want to make sure people
know about that you're working on
or yes please plug your stuff
now this is about julian i'm happy to do
this thanks for inviting me
and uh i look forward to doing it again
soon
thank you guys so much i'll selfishly
take you up on the offer and just
quickly say
please you guys are doing the work so
that's about it oh yeah
that's okay so i i run a newsletter on
whistleblower stories
uh covering whistleblower stories called
the dissenter it's at
dissenter.substance.com
free available and this is where you can
get all the latest updates on wikileaks
and other whistleblower stories
thank you okay we'll include that in the
description can we add things
we can add things in the description
right yeah i'm the tech challenge okay
we'll make sure to add everybody's stuff
in our description and we have a
a weekly gathering that john was
recently on
called codepink congress where we talk
about issues and then we take the time
out like we're doing today to actually
call and send emails and
that's at the website codepink.org
codepinkcongress
and we should do a whole event we get a
couple hundred people on each week so we
should do one on
julian and have everybody do what we're
doing today so thanks for the idea
absolutely anything and truthfully media
since you're local basically to me
anytime you call i'll come
so whatever whatever it is wonderful or
even different states
she well no she's down here or medivh's
in miami
i'm in dc right now i'm back and forth
but uh
i'll be there with you jen on the next
caravan on march 28th oh
that's i know why you're there media
it's to harass um
your victim um you know who you are
i i also like to harass marco rubio i
know where he lives
right but unlike um but rubio did not
accuse you of something that you clearly
didn't do
assault another story yeah for anybody
who's ever seen medea in person
and meant to think that somebody could
believe like physical assault
yeah it's really crazy incredibly
violent six foot plus woman
yeah well thank you so much for having
us on you guys
yes thank you guys so much really i
appreciate that thank you bye
thanks for watching if you want to
support our mission to transform
politics into service
please like this video subscribe follow
us on social media
and consider joining our patreon where
you'll get early access to our
interviews
as well as other exclusive content links
are in the description
peace out
you